redgiantsoftware.com 2019-09-03

# Red Giant | Privacy Policy

Red Giant, LLC (“ **Red Giant** ”) is committed to protecting your privacy. We have prepared this Privacy Policy to describe to you our practices regarding the personal information (as defined below) we collect from users of our website, located at _www.redgiant.com_ (the “ **Site** ”).

* Particularly Important Information

 **Who We Are:** For the purposes of applicable data protection legislation, the data control of your personal data is:

Red Giant, LLC  
Email: privacy@redgiant.com  
4230 SE King Rd  
Unit #345  
Portland, OR 97222

 **Must Read Sections:** We draw your attention in particular to the sections entitled “ **International Data Transfer** ” and “ **Your Rights** ”

Changes to this Policy: We will post any modifications or changes to this Privacy Policy on our Site. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so we encourage you to review it frequently. The “Last Revised” legend above indicates when this Privacy Policy was last changed. If we make any material changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you via email (if applicable) and/or post a notice on our Site prior to such changes taking effect.

* Purposes of Processing

 **What is personal data?**

We collect information about you in a range of forms, including personal data. As used in this Privacy Policy, “personal data” is as defined in the UK Data Protection Act 1998/the European Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC/General Data Protection Regulation 2018 and any successor legislation, this includes any information which, either alone or in combination with other information we hold about you, identifies you as an individual, including, for example, your name, postal address, email address and telephone number.

**Why do we need your personal data?**

We will only process your personal data in accordance with applicable data protection and privacy laws. We need certain personal data in order to provide you with access to the Site. If you created an account with us, you will have been asked to tick to agree to provide this information in order to access our services, purchase our products, view our content.

* A Note to Users Outside of the United States

If you are a non U.S. user of the Site, by visiting the Site and providing us with data, you acknowledge and agree that your personal information may be processed for the purposes identified in the Privacy Policy. In addition, your personal information may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of personal information may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By providing your data, you consent to such transfer.

* Types of Data We Collect

We collect information about you in the following ways:

  1. **Information You Provide to Us.**

– We may collect personal information from you, such as your name, e-mail and password when you create an account to log in to our network (“ **Account** ”). – When you order products on our Site, we will collect all information necessary to complete the transaction, including your name and billing information. – If you provide us feedback or contact us via e-mail, we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail, in order to send you a reply.  – When you post content (text, images, photographs, messages, comments or any other kind of content that is not your e-mail address) on our Site, the information contained in your posting will be stored in our servers and other users will be able to see it and any other information that you choose to make public on our Site. – When you participate in one of our surveys, we may collect additional profile information.  – We also collect other types of personal information that you provide to us voluntarily, such as your operating system and version, product registration number, and other requested information if you contact us regarding support for the Services.  – If you participate in a sweepstakes, contest or giveaway on our Site, we may ask you for your e-mail address and/or phone number (to notify you if you win or not). We may also ask for first and last names, and sometimes post office addresses to verify your identity. In some situations, we may need additional information as a part of the entry process, such as a prize selection choice. These sweepstakes and contests are voluntary. We recommend that you read the rules for each sweepstakes and contest that you enter.  – We may also collect personal information at other points in our Site that state that personal information is being collected.

  2. **Information Collected via Technology.**

 **Log Files.** As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (“ **ISP** ”), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users’ movements around the Site, gather demographic information about our user base as a whole, and better tailor our Site to our users’ needs. For example, some of the information may be collected so that when you visit the Site again, it will recognize you and the information could then be used to serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests. 

**Automated Decision Making and Profiling.**

We do not use your personal data for the purposes of automated decision-making. However, we may do so in order to fulfil obligations imposed by law, in which case we will inform you of any such processing and provide you with an opportunity to object.

* Cookies

 **What are cookies?**

We may collect information using “cookies.” Cookies are small data files stored on the hard drive of your computer or mobile device by a website. We may use both session cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent cookies (which stay on your computer or mobile device until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our Site.

We use two broad categories of cookies: (1) first party cookies, served directly by us to your computer or mobile device, which are used only by us to recognize your computer or mobile device when it revisits our Site; and (2) third party cookies, which are served by service providers on our Site, and can be used by such service providers to recognize your computer or mobile device when it visits other websites.

**Cookies we use**

Our Site uses the following types of cookies for the purposes set out below:

**Type of cookie** | **Purpose**  
---|---  
  
Essential Cookies

| 

These cookies are essential to provide you with services available through our Site and to enable you to use some of its features. For example, they allow you to log in to secure areas of our Site and help the content of the pages you request load quickly. Without these cookies, the services that you have asked for cannot be provided, and we only use these cookies to provide you with those services.  
  
Functionality Cookies

| 

These cookies allow our Site to remember choices you make when you use our Site, such as remembering your language preferences, remembering your login details and remembering the changes you make to other parts of our Site which you can customize. The purpose of these cookies is to provide you with a more personal experience and to avoid you having to re-enter your preferences every time you visit our Site.  
  
Analytics and Performance Cookies

| 

These cookies are used to collect information about traffic to our Site and how users use our Site. The information gathered does not identify any individual visitor. It includes the number of visitors to our Site, the websites that referred them to our Site, the pages they visited on our Site, what time of day they visited our Site, whether they have visited our Site before, and other similar information.  We use this information to help operate our Site more efficiently, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity on our Site.

We use Google Analytics for this purpose. Google Analytics uses its own cookies. It is only used to improve how our Site works. You can find out more information about Google Analytics cookies here: [https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies](https://www.google.com/url?q=https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies&sa=D&ust=1528386920376000)

You can find out more about how Google protects your data here: [www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html&sa=D&ust=1528386920377000).

You can prevent the use of Google Analytics relating to your use of our Site by downloading and installing the browser plugin available via this link: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl%3Den-GB&sa=D&ust=1528386920377000)  
  
Targeted and advertising cookies

| 

These cookies track your browsing habits to enable us to show advertising related to our products which is more likely to be of interest to you. These cookies use information about your browsing history to group you with other users who have similar interests. Based on that information, we may place cookies to to show adverts which we think will be relevant to your interests while you are on third party websites.

You can disable cookies which remember your browsing habits and target advertising at you by visiting [http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices&sa=D&ust=1528386920379000). If you choose to remove targeted or advertising cookies, you will still see adverts but they may not be relevant to you.  
  
**Disabling cookies**

You can typically remove or reject cookies via your browser settings. In order to do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “settings,” “help” “tools” or “edit” facility). Many browsers are set to accept cookies until you change your settings.

Further information about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your computer or mobile device and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.allaboutcookies.org&sa=D&ust=1528386920381000) and [www.youronlinechoices.com.uk](https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.youronlinechoices.com.uk&sa=D&ust=1528386920381000).

If you do not accept our cookies, you will experience some inconvenience in your use of our Site. For example, we may not be able to recognize your computer or mobile device and you may not be able to complete transactions in our online store.

* Pixel Tags

We may also use pixel tags (which are also known as web beacons and clear GIFs) on our Site to track the actions of users on our Site. Unlike cookies, which are stored on the hard drive of your computer or mobile device by a website, pixel tags are embedded invisibly on webpages. Pixel tags measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about usage of the Site, so that we can manage our content more effectively. The information we collect using pixel tags is not linked to our users’ personal data.

* Advertising

We may serve advertisements regarding our products when you visit and use the Site. We may collect and use click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over during your visits to the Site in order to provide advertisements about our products likely to be of interest to you. We use cookies to collect this information.

* Use of Your Personal Information 

  1. General Use. In general, personal information you submit to us is used either to respond to requests that you make, or to aid us in serving you better. We use your personal information in the following ways:

– facilitate the creation of and secure your Account on our network; – identify you as a user in our system; – provide improved administration of our Site; – provide the services you request; – improve the quality of experience when you interact with our Site;  – send you a welcome e-mail to verify ownership of the e-mail address provided when your Account was created; – send you administrative e-mail notifications, such as security or support and maintenance advisories; – with your consent, to send you marketing e-mails about upcoming promotions, and other news, including information about products and services offered by us and our affiliates. You may opt-out of receiving such information at any time: such marketing emails tell you how to “opt-out.” Please note, even if you opt out of receiving marketing emails, we may still send you non-marketing emails. Non-marketing emails include emails about your account with us (if you have one) and our business dealings with you; – respond to your inquiries related to employment opportunities or other requests; and – send newsletters, surveys, offers, and other promotional materials related to our Services and for other marketing purposes of Red Giant.

  2. User Testimonials and Feedback. We often receive testimonials and comments from users who have had positive experiences with our products. We occasionally publish such content. We may post user feedback, including your name and/or screen name used in posting such content, on the Site from time to time. If you make any comments on a blog or forum associated with our Site, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these blogs and forums.
  3. Creation of Anonymous Data. We may create anonymous data records from personal information by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the data personally identifiable to you. We use this anonymous data to analyze request and usage patterns so that we may enhance the content of our Site and improve Site navigation. We reserve the right to use Anonymous Data for any purpose and disclose Anonymous Data to third parties in our sole discretion.

* Disclosure of Your Personal Information

We disclose your personal information as described below and as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

  1. Third Party Service Providers. We may share your personal information with third party service providers to: provide you with the products and services that we offer you through our Site; to conduct quality assurance testing; to facilitate creation of accounts; to provide technical support; and/or to provide other services to Red Giant.
  2. Affiliates. We may share some or all of your personal information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (“Affiliates”), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.
  3. Corporate Restructuring. We may share some or all of your personal information in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisition or dissolution transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets. In the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership, personal information may also be transferred as a business asset. If another company acquires our company, business, or assets, that company will possess the personal information collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy.
  4. Other Disclosures. Regardless of any choices you make regarding your personal information (as described below), Red Giant may disclose personal information if it believes in good faith that such disclosure is necessary (a) in connection with any legal investigation; (b) to comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Red Giant; (c) to protect or defend the rights or property of Red Giant or users of the Site or Services; and/or (d) to investigate or assist in preventing any violation or potential violation of the law, this Privacy Policy, or our Terms of Use.

* Your Rights Regarding Information

You have several choices regarding the use of information on our Service:

  1. Email Communications. We will periodically send you free newsletters and e-mails that directly promote the use of our Site or products and services. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below). Despite your indicated e-mail preferences, we may send you service related communications, including notices of any updates to our Terms of Use or Privacy Policy.
  2. Access. You may access the information we hold about you at any time by contacting us directly.
  3. Amend. You can also contact us to update or correct any inaccuracies in your personal data.
  4. Move. Your personal data is portable – i.e. you to have the flexibility to move your data to others as you wish.
  5. Erase and forget. In certain situations, for example when the information we hold about you is no longer relevant or is incorrect, you can request that we erase your data.

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us using the details in Section 1 above. In your request, please make clear: (i) **what**  personal data is concerned; and (ii) **which of the above rights**  you would like to enforce. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the personal data associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable and in any event, within one month of your request. Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such change or deletion.

* Retention

We will only retain your personal data as long reasonably required for you to use the Site unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (for example for regulatory purposes).

* Sensitive Personal Data

Subject to the following paragraph, we ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive personal data (e.g., social security numbers, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion or other beliefs, health, biometrics or genetic characteristics, criminal background or trade union membership) on or through the Site or otherwise to us.

* Complaints

We are committed to resolve any complaints about our collection or use of your personal data. If you would like to make a complaint regarding this Privacy Policy or our practices in relation to your personal data, please contact us at: privacy@redgiant.com. We will reply to your complaint as soon as we can and in any event, within 45 days. We hope to resolve any complaint brought to our attention, however if you feel that your complaint has not been adequately resolved, you reserve the right to contact your local data protection supervisory authority, which for the UK, is the Information Commissioner’s Office.
